Guide to the Town and Campus Club Records, 1938-2019 and undated RL.11596
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Town and Campus Club records
1938-2019 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Town and Campus Club (Durham, N.C.)
RL.11596
4.3 Linear Feet
The Town and Campus Club is an woman's organization in Durham, North Carolina. It was founded in 1938 with the purpose "to follow the literary interests of the members and to promote friendship and social activity." The records of the Town and Campus Club primarily feature administrative and program records for the organization, including the constitution and by-laws, minutes, and treasurer's reports, as well other occasional records maintained by the secretary, along with program booklets, club histories, and member biographies and sketches. In addition, there is correspondence as well as color photographs, including two group photographs.
Arrangement
Organized into the following series: Administrative, Programs, Correspondence, and Photographs.
Biographical / Historical
The Town and Campus Club is an woman's organization in Durham, North Carolina. It was founded in 1938 with the purpose "to follow the literary interests of the members and to promote friendship and social activity."
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Town and Campus Club Records were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2018 and 2019.
Collection Overview
The records of the Town and Campus Club primarily feature administrative and program records for the organization, including the constitution and by-laws, minutes, and treasurer's reports, as well other occasional records maintained by the secretary, along with program booklets, club histories, and member biographies and sketches. In addition, there is correspondence as well as color photographs, including two group photographs.
Clubs -- North Carolina -- Durham; Literature -- Societies, etc.; Women -- North Carolina -- Societies and clubs; Durham (N.C.) -- Societies and clubs; Town and Campus Club (Durham, N.C.)
- Administrative, 1938-2019
  Scope and Contents
  The Administrative Series comprises the organization's constitution and by-laws, minutes, and treasurer's reports. In addition, there are four books maintained by the secretary (1938-1980) that include minutes, as well as treasurer's reports, program booklets, lists of officers and members, attendance records, occasional clippings, and a color group photograph of several of the founding members. There are also copies of the constitution and by-laws along with other administrative information in later program booklets in the Programs Series.
  - Constitution and by-laws, 1949?-2014 (Box 1)
  - Book I, 1938-1946 (Box 6)
    Contains secretary's reports, primarily minutes (1938-1946), but also lists of officers and members.
  - Book II, 1946-1980 (Box 7)
    Contains the secretary's records, including minutes (1946-1955), program booklets, lists of officers and members, and treasurer's reports. In the back of the volume is a list of officers, 1938-1980. Contents of a folder for correspondence and constitution and by-laws have been removed to their respective folders elsewhere in the collection.
  - Book III, 1955-1967 (Box 8)
    Contains secretary's and treasurer's records, including minutes and reports of attendance and account balances. There are also program booklets (pasted in), list of member birthdays, as well as lists of officers and members. Some program booklets have been foldered separately in the box.
  - Book IV, 1967-1980 (Box 9)
    Contains secretary's and treasurer's records, including minutes and reports of attendance and account balances. There are also program booklets (pasted in), as well as a few clippings and a color photograph.
  - Minutes, 1986-2019; 16 folders (Box 1)
    Minutes are maintained by fiscal year, e.g., 1986-87, 2016-17.
  - History of Officers and Presenters, 2018-2019 (Box 1)
  - Treasurer's reports, 2000-2009 (Box 1)
- Programs, 1957-2019 and undated
  The Programs Series primarily features program booklets (1957-2018), but there are also histories of the organization along with mystery member sketches and member biographies that were presented during club meetings. Includes a 2018 spreadsheet listing officers, program themes, and individual papers given since the founding of the organization. There are also a few artifacts from meetings, including menus and anniversary napkins. For earlier program booklets, see the books maintained by the secretary in the Administrative series.
  - Summary of officers, Annual theme, and paper titles 1938-2018 spreadsheet (Box 2)
  - Historical sketch, 1981 (Box 2)
    Sketch of the club's history, March and September 1981, by Dorothy Rankin. Transcribed and distributed to members in 2003.
  - Historical sketch, 1998 (Box 2)
    Handwritten summary of the 1981 historical sketch of the club's history by Margaret Hodel. For 60th anniversary.
  - Brief club history, 2005 (Box 2)
    Reproduced in annual programs.
  - Club history paper, 2009 (Box 2)
    By Mary Skinner, April 2009.
  - Program booklets, 1957-1996; 6 folders (Box 3)
  - Program booklets, 1996-2019; 7 folders (Box 4)
  - Mystery member sketches, 1957 and undated (Box 4)
  - Member biographies, undated (Box 4)
  - Menus, napkins, 2009-2018 and undated (Box 4)
- Correspondence, 1947-2018 and undated; 3 folders
  The Correspondence Series contains letters written to the organization by current and former members, letters of recognition for donations made by the club, letters offering potential membership, along with some tributes to members. Includes a few scattered program booklets and a bank statement.
  - Correspondence, 1947-2018 (Box 2)
- Photographs, 1980-1998 and undated
  The Photographs series contains color photographs taken during club gatherings. Includes two group photographs, one with members listed. Many of the photographs feature captions or identify those pictured. There are also individual images (printouts of photographs) included in later program booklets in the Programs Series.
  - Photographs, 1980-1998 and undated; 2 folders (Box 5)